Professional Profile

Senior Software Engineer with more than 10 years of experience in advanced computing technologies and full-stack tech-solutions development.

Proven experience in real-time ad-delivery systems, distributed data-store systems, live music/audio broadcast applications, and location-based & data-mobilization software solutions.

EXPERIENCE

• Amazon.com, Inc.

Jan 2020 - Present

Software Development Engineer II

- Ads Filtering & Eligibility Services: Designed a globally-accessible Ad Eligibility API that handles hundreds of transactions per second, utilizing API Gateway, Lambda, and DynamoDB GlobalTables to deliver a cross-regional distributed solution.
 - Developing next generation Ads Filtering service using various technologies such as AWS ECS and SQS.
- Amazon Music Amp: Amp is an infinite-dial digital radio broadcast mobile application. Amp allows users to create a show, go live, play music, and take in call-in guests all with simple flow and within minutes.
 - Lead engineer developing Amp Android app and migrating Amp iOS app to hybrid ReactNative-based architecture with native core components in both iOS Swift and Android Kotlin.
 - Team leader of Creator Studio & Call-in experience full-stack development maintaining iOS/Swift client and backend system using AWS Lambda, Chime APIs, Elastic-Containers on Fargate microservices, and AWS AppSync GraphQL.
 - Led group of engineers to develop iOS Bluetooth/audio solution which was filed as **Patent** P78152 SWITCHING WIRELESS PROFILES IN RESPONSE TO TRIGGER EVENTS.
- Ads Serving Core Engine: FenixSPService is orchestration engine that serves Sponsored-Products Ads on Amazon.com retail website and mobile app worldwide. FenixSPService is a high-throughput low-latency real-time distributed service that delivers curated ads per user.
 - Worked on migration to Native AWS (NAWS) delivering the first proof-of-concept of FenixSPService on the public/native offering of AWS ecosystem.
 - Identified +20 technical blockers, led team of engineers to develop simple workaround solutions, and eventually provided a risk-mitigation path for full migration and launch of the service.
 - Launching FenixSPService on Native AWS was later featured in AWS re:Invent 2021 Under the hood at Amazon Ads.
 - Participated in on-call and DevOps rotations; improving pipelines and monitoring to implement best practices of Continuous Integration & Delivery CI/CD.

• Webalo, Inc. Jul 2016 - Dec 2019

Software Engineer

- HTML Toolkit: Designed the architecture for a new HTML-based platform-agnostic UI widget rendering toolkit.

 Led a team of engineers to develop and migrate Webalo's User Agent applications to the new toolkit and retire the Java Canvas-based toolkit. Utilizing TypeScript and Web Components in Angular 7, Bootstrap, and JavaScript/CSS.
- CI/CD: Automated system build, execution of integration and end-to-end tests, and binaries distribution through using Git Hooks, **Jenkins**, and Shell scripting.
- Unit & Integration testing: Spearheaded the effort to set up and design system testing framework for developing integration tests.
 - Utilizing **TestNG** and **Mockito** for module testing and **Selenium** for end-to-end testing.

• Google, Inc.

Aug 2015 - Nov 2015

 $Software\ Engineering\ Intern$

• Sandlot: As part of the G-Tech team, integrated sentiment prediction into Google's partners management tool. Responsible for the design and implementation of the new feature using Python and AngularJS.

• Wireless Stars, LLC

Oct 2013 - May 2015

Software Engineer

• ARTS: System for road traffic estimation based on user cell-phone data analytics. Building Android SDK for location and sensor data collection.

Collaborating with research team on developing production ready algorithms and modules for data processing back-end system using **Spring Boot** and data pipeline through Apache Camel.

Responsible for implementation and testing of Kalman-filter user speed estimator.

Utilized PostGIS to implement spatial queries consumed by various modules of the system.

Implemented **Android** app that uses traffic SDK to push data to the back-end and query the system for estimated traffic state. The application was used by business team for demo/presentation and by the research team for system evaluation.

• EYE360: Augmented reality application providing bi-directional user interaction built using Unity3D and Qualcomm Vuforia SDK

• Alexandria University

Sep 2012 - Jan 2013

Teaching Assistant

o In Special Scientific Program (SSP): Teaching Introduction to Databases and Numerical Analysis courses.

Experience Areas & Tools¹

- Advanced Computing: Distributed Cloud Computing Global Geo-separated Data Stores Distributed Caching Serverless Architectures
- Data Protection and Cybersecurity: DDOS Protection, WAF, and API Authentication Protocols Cryptology and Data Privacy
- **Tech Business Domains**: E-Commerce and Advertising Music and Live Broadcast Digital Data Transformation Location-based Services Augment Reality
- Languages: Java Swift Python TypeScript HTML/JavaScript/CSS SQL
- Frameworks: iOS ReactNative Spring MVC/Boot Bootstrap Angular 7 Unity3D Android
- CI/CD: CDK- Jenkins TestNG Selenium Mockito/PowerMock Jasmine/Karma

EDUCATION

• Alexandria University, Faculty of Engineering

Sep 2007 - Jul 2012

B.Sc. Computer and Systems Engineering

Continuous Education ²

- Architecture and Developing on AWS: AWS Hands-on Training
- DevOps on AWS: AWS Hands-on Training
- Security Engineering on AWS: AWS Hands-on Training
- Programming Languages: Coursera Washington Uni
- Introduction to Functional Programming in Scala: Coursera
- Applied Cryptography: Udacity
- Introduction to Cryptography: Coursera Stanford
- Introduction to Recommender Systems: Coursera Uni of Minnesota
- Algorithms Design and Analysis: Coursera Stanford
- CSMM.102x Machine Learning: Edx ColumbiaX
- CSMM.101x Artificial Intelligence: Edx ColumbiaX
- Introduction to AI for Robotics: Udacity
- Machine Learning: Coursera
- Coding the Matrix: Coursera
- Scalable Machine Learning: Edx

¹Technologies are listed in decreasing order of experience.

²Certificates are available upon request.